Otto Klemperer Archive
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Books, 1901-1988 (Box 109-111, Open shelves)
  - Nolthenius, Hélène. Duecento: hohes Mittelalter in Italien. Würzburg: Werkbund, 1957., Annotated by Otto Klemperer.; Inscribed.; Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 4. (Box-folder 110/4)
  - Osborne, Charles and Kenneth Thomson, eds. Klemperer stories: anecdotes, sayings and impressions of Otto Klemperer. London: Robson Books, 1980., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: typed errata sheets; carbon of typed letter from Lotte Klemperer, May 31, 1980; typed letter from Jeremy Robson, June 10, 1980; typed letter from Charles Osborne, July 16, 1980; carbon of typed letter from Lotte Klemperer, July 4, 1980; typed letter from Lord Miles, July 11, 1980; carbon of typed letter from Lotte Klemperer, July 22, 1980; newspaper clipping, June 12, 1980.; Photocopies and originals filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 1. (Box-folder 111/1)
  - Osborne, Charles and Kenneth Thomson, eds. Otto Klemperer: Sagen Sie doch einfach Otto Anekdotisches. München and Zürich: R. Piper & Co., 1980., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: typed and signed note by Lotte Klemperer glued to inside front cover.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Ovid. Die erotischen Dichtungen. Translated by Viktor Marnitz. Stuttgart: Alfred Kröner, 1958., Signed by Otto Klemperer, 1958.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 1. (Box-folder 111/1)
  - Paul-Hindemith-Institut, ed. Hindemith-Jahrbuch, 1974/75/IV. Main: B. Schott's Söhne, 1975., Signed by unidentified person.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 1. (Box-folder 111/1)
  - Plessner, Helmuth. Conditio humana. Ullstein: Propyläen, n.d, Inscribed and signed by Helmuth Plessner.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 1. (Box-folder 111/1)
  - Plessner, Helmuth. Diesseits der Utopie. Ausgewählte Beiträge zur Kultursoziologie. Düsseldorf/Köln: Eugen Diederichs, 1966., Inscribed and signed by Helmuth Plessner, 1966.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 1. (Box-folder 111/1)
  - Presser, J. Ashes in the wind. Pomerans, Arnold, trans. London: Souvenir Press, 1968., Annotated by Otto Klemperer.
  - Prieberg, Fred K. Kraftprobe Wilhelm Furtwängler im Dritten Reich. Wiesbaden: F. A. Brockhaus, 1986., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 2. (Box-folder 111/2)
  - Reich, Willi, ed. Gustav Mahler: im eigenen Wort--im Worte der Freunde. Zürich: Im Verlag der Arche, 1958., Signed by Otto Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 3. (Box-folder 110/3)
  - Riessler, Paul, trans. Die heilige Schrift des alten und des neuen Bundes. Zürich: K. H. Pfister, 1952., Inscribed and signed.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 2. (Box-folder 111/2)
  - Rösch, Konstantin, trans. Das neue Testament. Paderborn: Ferdinand Schöningh, 1946., Annotated and signed by Otto Klemperer.; Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 2. (Box-folder 111/2)
  - Rossetti, William Michael, ed. The poetical works of Lord Byron. London: Ward, Lock, & Co., n.d., Inscribed and signed by unidentifed person.; Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 2. (Box-folder 111/2)
  - Rozhdestvenskii, Gennadii. Thoughts about music. Moskva: Vsesoiuznoe Izdatel'stvo, 1975., Inscribed by Lotte Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 2. (Box-folder 111/2)
  - Saz, Natalia. Kinder im Theater: Erinnerungen. Translated by Hans Rodenberg. Berlin: Henschel, 1966., Inscribed.; Two photographs glued to front cover and title page.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 2. (Box-folder 111/2)
  - Saz, Natalia. Novellen meines Lebens. Translated by Erich Ahrndt. Berlin: Henschelverlag Kunst und Gesellschaft, 1986., Inscribed and signed by Natalia Saz.; Laid in: typed note by Lotte Klemperer glued to front cover.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 2. (Box-folder 111/2)
  - Saz, Natalia. Novellen meines Lebens. Translated by Hans Rodenberg. Berlin: Henschelverlag, 1973., Signed by Natalia Saz.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 2. (Box-folder 111/2)
  - Schaber, Will. Benedikt Fred Dolbin: Vortrag zur Eröffnung der Ausstellung Benedikt Fred Dolbin: Kopfstenogramme für die Berliner Presse 1926-1933 in der Deutscher Bibliothek 26 März 1980. Frankfurt am Main: Buchhändler-Vereinigung GmbH, 1980., Inscribed and signed by Will Schaber, 1981.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 2. (Box-folder 111/2)
  - Scheler, Max. Vom Ewigen im Menschen. Edited by Maria Scheler. Bern: Francke, 1954., Annotated and signed by Otto Klemperer, 1969.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 2. (Box-folder 111/2)
  - Schumacher, Karl von. Mirabeau: Aristokrat und Volkstribun. Stuttgart: Scherz & Goverts, 1954., Signed by Otto Klemperer, 1962.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 3. (Box-folder 111/3)
  - Schumann, Robert. Musikalische Haus- und Lebensregeln. Edited by Arbeitskreis für Haus- und Jugendmusik. Kassel: Im Bärenreiter, n.d., Signed by Otto Klemperer, 1962.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 3. (Box-folder 111/3)
  - Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth. On and off the record: a memoir of Walter Legge. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1982., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: newspaper clippings of book review in English and German.; Typed notes by Lotte Klemperer, three pages.; Filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 3. (Box-folder 111/3)
  - Schweitzer, Albert. J. S. Bach; Vorrede von Charles Marie Widor. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1915., Inscribed and signed by Gertrud Marcus, 1917.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 3. (Box-folder 111/3)
  - Siegele, Ulrich. Zwei Kommentare zum "Marteau sans maitre" von Pierre Boulez. Neuhausen-Stuttgart: Hänssler, 1979., Signed by Ulrich Siegele, Nov. 1979.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 3. (Box-folder 111/3)
  - Spinoza, Baruch de. Ethik. Translated by Otto Baensch. Leipzig: Felix Meiner, n.d., Annotated and signed by Otto Klemperer, 1916.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 3. (Box-folder 111/3)
  - Stader, Maria. Nehmt meinen Dank: Erinnerungen. Translated by Robert D. Abraham. München: Kindler, 1979., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: typed note by Lotte Klemperer glued to third page.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 4. (Box-folder 111/4)
  - Sternberg, Elli. Aus Briefen von Elli Sternberg., Handwritten in unknown hand.; Includes two photographs.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 4. (Box-folder 111/4)
  - Strawinsky, Igor. Gespräche mit Robert Craft. Translated by Manfred Gräter, H. J. Schatz, G. W. Baruch, and Martin Hürlimann. Zürich: Atlantis, 1961., Signed by Igor Stravinsky.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 4. (Box-folder 111/4)
  - Stravinsky, Vera and Robert Craft. Stravinsky in pictures and documents. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1978., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Signed by Werner Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 4. (Box-folder 111/4)
  - Thompson, Oscar. Debussy: man and artist. New York: Tudor, 1940., Signed by Otto Klemperer, 1917.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 4. (Box-folder 111/4)
  - Traber, Habakuk and Elmar Weingarten, eds. Verdrängte Musik: Berliner Komponisten im Exil. Berlin: Argon, 1987., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: carbon of typed letter dated 1987 Dec. 15.; Photocopies and original filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
  - Traub, Rainer and Harald Wiese, eds. Gespräche mit Ernst Bloch. Frankfurt am Main: Suhrkamp, 1975., Signed by Ernst and Karola Bloch, 1975.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
  - Trotski, Leon. Stalin: an appraisal of the man. Edited and translated by Charles Malamuth. London: Hollis and Carter, Ltd., 1947., Signed by Otto Klemperer, 1947.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
  - Vatikan. Lateinisch-Deutsches Volksmessbuch. Einsiedeln/Köln: Benziger & Co., 1938., Signed by Otto Klemperer, 1958.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
  - Viertel, Salka. The kindness of strangers. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1969., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: two newspaper clippings; two magazine clippings; one black and white photograph.; Photocopies and originals filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
  - Wegele, Ludwig. Der Lebenslauf der Marianne Thekla Mozart. Edited by Deutsche Mozartgesellschaft. Augsburg: Die Brigg, n.d., Signed by Ludwig Wegele.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
  - Weininger, Otto. Geschlecht und Charakter: eine prinzipielle Untersuchung. Wien: Wilhelm Braumüller, 1947., Annotated by Otto Klemperer.; Laid in: newpaper clipping, 1980 Nov. 1.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
  - Willnauer, Franz and Marina Mahler-Fistoulari, eds. Anna Mahler sculptures. Salzburg: Roser Printing, 1988., Signed by Anna Mahler.; Laid in: four newspaper clippings (one photocopy), 1988 Aug.; Photocopies and originals filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
  - Ziegler, Richard. Klemperer probt die Johannespassion., Signed by R. Ziegler.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archives, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
  - Zudeick, Peter. Der Hintern des Teufels: Ernst Bloch--Leben und Werk. Moos & Baden-Baden: Elster, 1985., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
  - Zweig, Stefan. Romain Rolland: der Mann und das Werk. Frankfurt am Main: Rütten & Loening, 1921., Inscription and signature are illegible.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 5. (Box-folder 111/5)
Appendix: Index Linking Original Folder Numbers by Lotte Klemperer to Locations in the Otto Klemperer Archive
1 Heyworth CBC interview, “Urtexte,” 9/2-5/1969 48/1-2
2 Heyworth CBC interviews, 1969, 1970, 1972 48/1-4
4 Bregstein interview with Otto Klemperer 47/8
4 Bregstein interview with Lotte Klemperer and filmscript 47/6
4 Bregstein interview with Katja Mann 55/13
5 Universal Edition correspondence 45/7-9
6 B. Schott’s Söhne 45/2
7 Heyworth interview, 1969, West German Radio 48/5-6
8 Broadcasts by and about Otto Klemperer 47/5, 9-10; 48/7
47 Radio programs about the Kroll Opera 51/1-3
53 Los Angeles Philharmonic programs, 1933-1939 51/20-23
72 Rée family 45/1
73 Family biographical papers 44/100, 106/5
74 Family papers - register 44/3
75 Family biographical papers 44, 100, 106, MapCase 3
80 California State University 45/3
80 Royal Academy of Music 45/5
80 Santa Monica College 45/6
81 United States press clippings, 1926-1972 106/6
82 Otto Klemperer/Hilborn files; Loeb and Loeb 49/11-13
82 Citizenship certificates/passports 49/2
82 Life insurance 49/6
83 Freedom of Information Act; State Department files 49/1-10
Notebook A Kroll Opera 50, 51
Notebook B Otto Klemperer writings/statements 46
Notebook C Articles about Otto Klemperer 47